SOMU YADAV

IOS DEVELOPER

INFO

ADDRESS

9,vidya nagar,bhawarkuan,indore, Indore, 452001, India

PHONE

6265834002

EMAIL

somendra.sy@gmail.com

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

20 Oct 1996 bhopal

NATIONALITY

Indian

LINKS

github.com/SomuYadav

llinkedin.com/in/somendrayadav/

twitter.com/Somendra_Dev

<u>StackOverflow:</u>

<u>somuyadav</u>

SKILLS

iOS Development

Swift

UIKit

JSON CoreData

Adaptive Layout

CI/CD

CallKit App Extension

SDK Development With Cocoa Pods

SwiftUI

App Architecture

Design Patterns

PROFILE

I am a very curious and creative in iOS Development and In my 2 year experience I tried to built inventive and productive mobile application within a very scalable & optimized way. I always try to do something different

In iOS and iOS is my platform of choice,I still treat myself like a student and always learn like a student. I always try to give my best in my work because I love a lot with my work. I believe in creative and productive development. I have done research & development based work in iOS. i h've built application from scratch trying to use the best practices, architectures, patterns.

I have worked with product teams in various domain like Social Media,E-commerce, Health Care, Real - State,Tourism etc.

Apart from that I also meet people from outside to explore knowledge and attend tech meet-up.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

iOS Developer, Dexbytes Infotech

indore

Aug 2018 — Aug 2019

In this company I got an opportunity to build application from scratch as lead of project, also I have done research

& development based work in Call Kit App Extension & CoreML and I learn code optimization, design patterns, pixel to pixel design development.

iOS Developer, Consagous Technology

indore

Aug 2019 — Apr 2020

In consagous I also got opportunity in beacon based Core bluetooth gaming application. First time i worked on a very create & innovative social media platform POSITOOT, in this application developed soo many features like Facebook.

PROJECTS

POSITOOT

indore

Aug 2019 — Apr 2020

Description: POSITOOT

is an Enterprise application for IOS and android both the platform. The purpose of this

application is to set a positive environment and to give positive vibes . POSITOOT is a social application to share

positive posts, positive TOOTs and to set positive and user friendly environments for

Duration: 9 months

Team Size: 1

LANGUAGES

Hindi

.

English

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Responsibilities:-

- · Developed the Line-up module of the App.
- · Worked on Both UI as well as logical part.
- · Coordinate with other departments for web service and UI design.
- · Communicate technical issues/decisions.
- · Worked closely with Android developer's team for syncing iOS.
- Technology used: Xcode 11.2.1,Swift 5.1, RestAPI ,FCM, Bar Graph representation, Pod Installation,

Chat(One-to-one, Group chat), Socket, Notification center, observer pattern, MVP(Architecture).

Link

https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/positoot-a-revolutionary-twist-to-social-media#/

P-POG Indore

Aug 2019 — Present

Description: Play Our Game (P-POG) is a fun and exciting contest-based game in which players earn virtual "coins" by

being near one another and by visiting in-game locations. The player with the most coins at the end of the game

wins a cash prize! In order to collect coins you need to be within the range of another player, so meet new friends

or bring your friends along and explore your community to collect coins. Businesses and other locations around

your community serve as beacons -- areas where you can collect coins -- and the more you visit the more coins

you'll be eligible to collect.

Duration: 3 months(worked duration)

Team Size: 2

Responsibilities:-

- · Worked on UI Design of the application (Only Onboarding Module (15 Screens)).
- · Also worked on the animation Part of the Application.
- · Coordinate with other departments for web service and UI design.
- · Communicate technical issues/decisions.
- · Beacon Research & Development.
- · Bluetooth Integration.
- Technology used: Xcode 10.2,Swift 4.0, RestAPI, Animation, and Pod Installation, Accent Beacon

,Bluetooth, Socket, Notification center, observer pattern, MVP(Architecture).

Flexiasia Indore

Aug 2018 — Aug 2019

Description: This is an room booking application, in hotels and this application is developed in iOS and android

platform, this is an IOT functional app and in this application we have three phases, first one is manager,

second is user and third one is Technician. Two Phases Manager and user developed in iOS . in this app We $\,$

have used sinch for app to app calling and We have integrated automated door unlock functionality with

help of bluetooth.

Duration: 8 months

Team Size: 2

Responsibilities:-

- · Worked on UI as well as Coding part.
- · Changing the Project from XIB to Storyboards.
- · Understand the Sinch library.
- · Understand the bluetooth integration.
- · Communicate technical issues/decisions.
- Technology used: Xcode 10.2,Swift 4.0, RestAPI, Animation, and Pod Installation, AFNetworking, XIB, Pod

Installation, Voip(For app to app call), Multiple Storyboards, Notification Center, Delegates, FCM

Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/developer/flexiasia/id1465686069

Aircon indore

Aug 2018 — Present

Description: Aircon is an application for AC Booking, repairing, this application is developed in iOS and android

platform. in this application we have three phases, first one is Technician, second is user and third one is

manager for assign a technician to user.

Duration: 6 months

Team Size: 1

Responsibilities:-

- · Worked on UI as well as Coding part.
- · Worked on Storyboards.
- · Communicate technical issues/decisions.
- · Worked closely with Android developer's team for syncing iOS.
- Technology used: -Swift, JSON API Integration, Auto Layout, User Defaults, Cocoa-pods, Cosmos-View ,

Custom Sky Floating , Google Map, Facebook Integration, Gmail integration, FCM, Multiple Storyboards,

Notification Center, Delegates, Refactor Storyboard.

Kashish (A Feedback of Shopping)

indore

Jul 2018 — Jul 2018

Description: Kashish is an only shopping feedback application,In This Application User Can Give Our Shopping

Feedback on Successful Sale Or Loss Of Sale.

Duration: 1 month

Team Size: 1

Responsibilities:-

- Worked on UI as well as Coding part.
- Worked on Storyboards.
- · Worked closely with Android developer's team for syncing iOS.
- · Communicate technical issues/decisions.
- Technology used: Swift, SQLite, Core Data, JSON API Integration, Auto Layout, User Defaults, SVG Font

Integration, Cocoa-pods, Cosmos View, Custom Sky Floating.

Link: https://apps.apple.com/ee/app/kashish-feedback/id1437711146

iCares Malaysia

Sep 2019 — Nov 2020

Description: iCARES, stands for Integrated Community and Resident System. iCARES was designed and built to creates a caring community, build a convenience, safe and secure living environment in mind. This app aims to connect between Resident, JMB/MC, Building Management and Security.

iCARES strives to bring happy, convenience, safe and secure to all community by providing features:

- 1) Announcement & Notice Board
- 2) Report & Complaint
- 3) Emergency
- 4) Maintenance Fees
- 5) My Visitor
- 6) and many more...

This app's Visitor feature provides community and resident a simple, easy yet secure solution in managing visitor without losing its hospitality. The visitor management system paired with standalone Security App.

Duration: 6 month (Worked duration)

Team Size: 2

Responsibilities:-

- · Developed the Line-up module of the App.
- · Worked on Both UI as well as logical part.
- · Coordinate with other departments for web service and UI design.
- · Communicate technical issues/decisions.
- Worked closely with Android developer's team for syncing iOS.
- Technology used: Xcode 10.2 ,Swift 4.2, RestAPI ,FCM, Shimmer Effect

Chat (One-to-one chat), observer pattern, MVP (Architecture).

Link: https://apps.apple.com/my/app/icares-community-app/id1472689576

RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT

TEXT READER(Machine learning)

Indore

Oct 2019 — Oct 2020

Description: This application is developed for client requirement, in this application is useful to process a image text

and it can read a text of image.

Responsibilities:-

- \cdot Worked on UI as well as Coding part.
- · Stand Alone Application.
- · Worked on CoreML Framework of iOS.
- · Technology used: Swift , CoreML, AutoLayout, Storyboard.

BLOQ(CALL Blocking App)

San Jose

Oct 2019 — Oct 2019

Description: This is a charity purpose app for blocking spam calls And when a large number of users block a

particular then this blocked number will add another users block list

Responsibilities:-

· Worked on UI as well as Coding part.

- · Stand Alone Application.
- · Worked Call Directory App Extension(complicated part).
- · Communicate technical issues/decisions.
- Technology used: Swift, JSON API Integration, Auto Layout, User Defaults, Call Directory app extension.

EDUCATION

10th, N.S.V.M, Hoshangabad

Hoshangabad

Aug 2020 — Aug 2020

I was curious student in my class, I love a lot with math & Science, I was a second rank holder in my class and also got distinction all subject and I have done 10th with 83%.

12th, Govt. Higher Secondary School, Hoshangabad.

Hoshangabad

Aug 2020 — Aug 2020

I am very much interested in physics, I was a second rank holder in my class. I used to do creative and innovative things and i have done 12th with 79%.

B.E, Swami Vivekanand College of Engineering, Indore(M.P)

indore

Jul 2014 — Aug 2018

I was a highly dedicated student in tech and very curious to do something innovative things. I have worked on a very good projects in my college like recommendation engine, Mood based music system, Book Mob(Own Product)

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Participant, Swift India Indore

indore

Aug 2019 — Present

Participant, Hacker Rank

indore

Oct 2018 — Dec 2020